Let's learn about a new data structure called Q.
AQ is a useful data structure in programming.
It's similar to this ticket queue outside a cinema hall where the first person entering the queue is
the first person who gets the ticket.
Hugh falls the first and first tore through the fee for the item that goes in.
The first is the item that comes out first.
OK.
So.
How to add elements, we are going to see that basic the ink and deck adding and removing elements in
the queue as the presentation and animation and next video, we are going to go deep and inside this
operation and see the current.
We have three elements, and this is their cue.
We need to add that cue.
We need to 8q the elements one, two and three inside the queue, so.
By calling in Q1, this is the method that will add the element one inside the queue would be called.
Then if we call in Q2, we are going to add that element to inside the queue.
If we in Q3, it will add the Element three inside this queue.
OK, now let's remove the items from that queue.
It called Dec, not the queue.
It is called Dec, so we consider this queue.
We have three, two and one.
Their first element that we have inserted is one and we need to dec.
So if we called the the method DEC, we will remove the first element that have been entered inside
this queue.
So we're going to remove number one.
If we call the method their game deck, so number two would be removed because it will.
It is on the top.
If we call deck again, it will remove number three.
So these are their basic operations and a queue is an object or an absolute data structure.
ADT that allows the following operation.
We have learned about in queue deck and we have also is empty.
We check if the queue is empty is full to check is that queue is full and peak to get the value of the
front of the queue without removing it.
We will learn how to create these methods in the next videos and see and we go, we are going to see
in the Java language how these methods and how to implement a queue.